## Ivan Starodubtsev Senior C/Linux Software Engineer

## **Personal info**

Date of birth: November 13, 1986
Family status: married, 1 child



## **Executive Summary**

- Linux software developer with strong user space development experience and basic kernel space development experience in C/C++ using all available GNU/Linux & UNIX tools.
- Overall experience in software development counts all years from **2010** till present.
- Experience in full software development process using different tools for version control, building the project code, code review, debug, automation, applications profiling etc.

Technical Skills	
Software Skills Category	Skill Sub Category
Functional Area	Software engineering and development primarily for embedded systems with/for Linux or other operating systems
Software Development Methodologies	Agile, Scrum, TDD
Programming Languages	C/C++(basic)/Java (basic)/Python (basic)/Lua (basic)/Bash/Sh
Operating Systems	Linux (host, target)/Windows (host)/VxWorks (target)/QNX (target)
Network	TCP/IP, UDP protocols
VCS	ClearCase, SVN, git (repo-git-gerrit-jenkins/branching model)
Development Tools	All available from GNU/Linux system environment (coreutils/binutils/gcc/gdb/make etc.) and other widely spread UNIX tools, custom and highly specialized scripting tools, MathCAD, MATLAB/Simulink, Coverity, Valgrind
Standardized Technologies	MPEG, DVB(-S/T/C), HDTV, POSIX
Specific Libraries	Cairo 2D graphics library, Skia 2D graphics library, libpcap
Other software skills	Unit testing, Test cases development, Linux administration, DevOps (basics), Project infrastructure creation and maintaining using different tools
Additional Skills Category	Skill Sub Category
Academic skills	Mathematics (Higher and Calculus, Discrete, Statistical), Physics, Radioelectronics, Analogue and Digital Circuitry, Computer Science, Automation and Control Theory
Personal skills	Inquiring Mind, "Can-do" Attitude to Solving Tasks

Foreign language skills		
Skill Category	Spoken	Written
English	Upper-intermediate	Upper-intermediate

Education	
Entity:	KhAI (Kharkiv Aviation Institute), Kharkiv, Ukraine
Dates attended:	September 2004 - February 2010

**Qualifications:** Master's Degree

**Faculty:** Radio Technical Systems of Aircraft **Specialization area:** Electronics and Telecommunications

Phone: +380 67 9262642 | Skype ID: ivan.starodubtsev.skype | Email: ivan.starodubtsev.name@gmail.com | CV: CV.pdf

## **Professional Experience Summary**

Company: "Insart Ltd.", Ukraine, Kharkiv, 18 Gudanova str.

**Duration:** August 2015 - Present **Role:** Senior Software Engineer

Project Description: Security device application for smart homes/IoT protection, System

applications

Responsibilities: Applications development, Build system development, Code review,

Bugs/Issues fixing, Project specific tools development, Profiling of applications

**Technologies (common):** C/C++, GNU/Linux/Debian, ARM, MIPS, GCC, GDB, Valgrind, Bootloaders, Command line interface, make build systems, shell scripting, TCP/IP, tcpdump.

• Company: LLC "EchoStar Ukraine", Ukraine, Kharkiv, 63 Kolomens'ka str.

**Duration:** July 2013 - July 2015 **Role:** Software Engineer

**Project Description:** Set-top boxes user applications, System applications

**Responsibilities:** Applications development, Build system development, Code review, Bugs/Issues fixing, Unit testing and test cases development, Project documentations development, Project specific tools development, Profiling of applications

**Technologies (common):** C/C++, GNU/Linux, ARM, MIPS, GCC, GDB, Valgrind, Bootloaders, Command line interface, make build systems, shell scripting, Unit testing, Software security/encryption aspects, TCP/IP.

**Technologies (proprietary):** Broadcom SDK (Nexus)

Company: GlobalLogic, Ukraine, Lviv, 26 Sheptytskykh str.

**Duration:** December 2012 - June 2013

Role: Software Engineer

**Project Description:** Board support package (BSP)

**Responsibilities:** Device drivers development, Build system development, Code review, Bugs/Issues fixing, Project specific tools development, Project documentations development **Technologies (common):** C, VxWorks, ARM, GCC, Bootloaders, make build systems, shell

scripting

Technologies (proprietary): WindRiver workbench environment

• Company: LLC "EchoStar Ukraine", Ukraine, Kharkiv, 63 Kolomens'ka str.

**Duration:** November 2011 - November 2012

Role: Software Engineer

**Project Description:** Set-top boxes automated test system applications, System applications **Responsibilities:** Applications development, Build system development, Code review,

Bugs/Issues fixing, Project documentations development

**Technologies (common):** C/C++, GNU/Linux, ARM, MIPS, GCC, GDB, Bootloaders, Command

line interface, make build systems, shell scripting **Technologies (proprietary):** Broadcom SDK (Nexus)

Company: PJSC SRPA "Impulse", Ukraine, Luhansk region, Severodonetsk, Pobedy sq. 2

**Duration:** April 2010 - October 2011

Role: Software Engineer

**Project Description:** Instrumentation & control (I&C) systems for automation of large industrial facilities (nuclear/heat power plants, railway transportation automated management centers & systems)

**Responsibilities:** Instrumentation & control (I&C) systems software development, Project documentations development, Product functional testing

**Technologies (common):** C, ARM, Cortex-M3, STMicroelectronics STM32 MCUs, IAR Embedded Workbench for ARM, Device drivers development

**Technologies (proprietary):** I&C systems engineering technology in area of railway transportation